

Anton Eprev

Amsterdam, Netherlands +31 6 27 61 58 93 a.eprev@gmail.com http://eprev.org

ABOUT ME

I clearly remember writing programs in BASIC sitting next to Soviet Union clone of DEC Pro-350 – *Elektronica 85*. What a time it was! Only later there were x86, Pascal and the first steps in OOP. Looking back now, it was a long adventure for me to become a web developer. Before that, there were enjoyable moments in the university: programming in C and ASM, INT 13H, disassembling, UNIX, sockets, Knuth's TAOCP. It was awesome! Then there were a lot of machine-learning stuff and functional programming while studying for Ph.D. Oh, boy... I enjoy and appreciate it all. And at the same time, over the last nine years, there have been HTML and Javascript.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

I like: javascript, jquery, extjs, node.js, python, erlang, html, sass, github, api, c, sql, machine-learning, latex, performance, bem, go.

EXPERIENCE

Client Side Developer, Booking.com, Amsterdam — July 2014-Present

Booking.com is the world leader in booking accommodation online.

Senior Developer, Mail.ru Group, Moscow — September 2011-June 2014

Project: Futubra (09.2011–09.2012)

Startup. Microblogging service (shut down).

- 1. Arranged front-end development and deploying processes (adaptive design, Sass, BEM/OCSS, unobtrusive JS, obfuscation of JS using GCC).
- 2. Created <u>Linux service</u> for rendering JavaScript templates on the server-side (Node.js).
- 3. Contributed to <u>Fest</u> JavaScript templates (bug fixing, a lot of optimizations, maintaining NPM).

Project: Mail.ru (10.2012–07.2014)

Russia's leading email service and largest Internet portal.

- 1. Took a part in creating Linux service (written in C++) for rendering JavaScript templates on the high-loaded server-side (V8).
- 2. Created a toolkit for rapid prototyping and building mobile and touch-based web applications (Node.js, BEM, bem-tools, fest). All mobile-friendly portal projects (news, auto, afisha, lady, weather, sport, tv and hi-tech) are powered by the created toolkit.
- 3. Maintaining and contributing to <u>Fest</u> (i18n).

Role: Front-End development team leader (8 developers) (10.2013–07.2014)

1. Technical management and problem solving.

Project: My.com (08.2013–07.2014)

My.com offers communication and entertainment products.

- 1. Took a part in development of home page and portal navigation (bem, git, grunt).
- 2. Lead front-end development team.

Professor, Mail.ru Group, Moscow — September 2013-June 2014

Taught students about the front-end development at <u>Tech-Mail.ru</u>. Lectures are available at <u>tp.eprev.org</u> (Russian).

Web Developer, ActForex, Omsk — July 2007-August 2011

ActForex offers white-label platform for electronic Forex trading.

- 1. Markup HTML, CSS and Javascript for all UIs for back-office of trading system (javascript, extjs, svn).
- 2. Support web-based mobile trading application (plsql, oracle, svn).
- 3. Involved in the development of Java servlet-based back-office for trading system (java, maven, svn).

Assistant of Computer Science Department, Omsk State University — September 2008– June 2009

Taught students about operation systems (unix, c, bash).

Senior Developer, Sibek, Omsk — January 2004–July 2007

- 1. Developed content management system for company's website (php, html, mysql, javascript, cvs).
- 2. Developed web-based system to manage manufacturing processes (php, xul, javascript, firebird, cvs).
- 3. Developed software for wheel balancing machine (linux, c, c++, arm, cvs).

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Physics and Mathematics, Omsk State University — 2008–2011

Text categorization using word sense disambiguation.

M.S. Mathematics and Computer Science, Omsk State University — 2002–2008

Majored in computer security. With honors.